Guide to the Danbury Preservation Trust Records MS 039
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Series III: Projects
  - Historic Resources Inventory
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - 49 - 104 Garfield, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 47)
      Historic resources inventory sheets - 49 to 104 Garfield Ave.
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey 59 - 103 Garfield, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 48)
      Historic resources inventory sheets 59 to 103 Garfield Ave.
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - George, Grand, Great Plain, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 49)
      Historic resources inventory sheets George St, Grand St., Great Plain Rd.,
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - Harding, Harmony, Hayestown, Housman, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 50)
      Historic resources inventory sheets - Harding Place, Harmony St, Hayestown Rd, Housman St.
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - Jefferson, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 51)
      Historic resources inventory sheets - Jefferson Ave. with separate picutres
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey Lincoln, Linden, Long Ridge, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 52)
      Historic resources inventory sheets - Lincoln Ave, Linden Pl, Long Ridge Rd.,
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - Mountainville, 1983- 1986 (Box 7, Folder 53)
      Historic resources inventory sheets - Mountainville Rd. wit separate photos
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - Ohetayah, Orchard, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 54)
      Historic resources inventory sheets - Oheyatah Pl, Orchard St.,
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - Park Ave., Pearl St, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 55)
      Historic resources inventory sheets - Park Ave, (pictures need sleeves), Pearl St.
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - Pleasant St, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 56)
      Historic resources inventory sheets - Pleasant St., (pictures need sleeves),
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - Quien, Seeley, Southern Blvd, Spruce, Stadley Rough, Starrs Plain, Sugar Hollow, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 57)
      Historic resources inventory sheets - Quien St, Seeley St., Southern Blvd, Spruce St., Stadley Rough Rd., Starrs Plain Rd, Sugar Hollow Rd.
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey Terrace PL., 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 58)
      Historic Resources inventory sheets - Terrace Pl,
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - Washington Ave., 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      Historic resources invetory sheets - Washington Ave.
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - West St., 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 60)
      Historic resources inventory sheets - West St.
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - West Wooster St., 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 61)
      Historic resources inventory sheets, separate pictures - West Wooster St.
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - George St., 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
      George St. - ownership notes, assessor cards notes
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - Pleasant St, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
      Pleasant St - assessor's cards notes and handwritten ownership histories
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - West Wooster St, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 27-28)
      West Wooster St. - copies of map, handwritten chart and notes on ownership history, assessor's cards notes, architectural eval. Forms, West Wooster St. - historic resources inventory forms
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - Park Ave., 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 32-35)
      Park Ave. - ownership history notes, historic resources inventory forms; 2-4 to 106-108 Park Ave. - handwritten ownership notes, assessor's cards notes, some architectural eval. Forms, Ryder geneology - Ryders on Pleasant St, Park Ave.?; 2-4 to 28-30 Park Ave; 32-34 to 106-108; handwritten chart; 6 to 106-108 Park Ave. assessor's cards notes, architectual evaluation forms
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey -Deer Hill & Sugar Hollow areas background materials, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 36-38)
      Handwritten history of hatting firms around West St., Irish immigrants, other immigrant groups - Elm, Spring, Montgomvery Sts. Stevens St., Octagon House mentioned, miscellaneous notes on Deer Hill Ave, Park Ave. Notes on Oehyatah, Pleasant, Boughton, Bank, Bennett Pl., Cherry, Sugar Hollow (Rte. 7), Starrs Plain, Williams St, copies of News Times articles, copies of postcards, Mountainville - Abraham Waring notes, 56 - 58 Wooster Heights (one of 7 oldest) Washington, 94 Deer Hill, Great Plain, Foster St., Trowbidge geneology pages., 18 Brushy Hill - Parks property,
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - indexes of photos, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 39-43)
      Photo Indexes listed by Street and by number, includes contact sheets and negatives. Also a listing of historic names of houses- typed and handwritten copies
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey- Whitlock, 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Historic Resource inventory sheets - Whitlock St.
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - William St., 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Historic Resources inventory sheets - William St. 5-7 to 38
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - William, Wilson, Wooster, 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Historic resources inventory sheets - William St. 44-57; Wilson St., Wooster St.
    - Phase V: Deer Hill Avenue Survey - reports and correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
      Funding agreement, budget notes, 1985 survey time sheets, maps, grant correspondence
    - Phase VI: Northwest Neighborhood Survey - survey report, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Compreshensive survey Phase VI - report
    - Phase VI: Northwest Neighborhood Survey - - indexes and contact sheets, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Index to survey forms Phase VI Northeast neighborhood, contact sheets of building pictures with index
    - Phase VI: Northwest Neighborhood Survey -streets A to F, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Historic resources inventory sheets, separate phtos Abbott Ave, Beaver St, Beckett St. Clifton Pl., Duck St., Davis St., Fairlawn Ave., Farview Ave.
    - Phase VI: Northwest Neighborhood Survey - streets F to L, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      Historic resources inventory sheets Franklin St, Grandview Ave., Highland Ave, Hoyt St., Knapps La, Lake Ave., separate photos; Picture of Hurlbut house as found on historic map
    - Phase VI: Northwest Neighborhood Survey - streets M to R, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      Historic resources inventory sheets Mallory St, Rose St., Morris St., Robinson Ave., Rose Hill Ave., separate photos
    - Phase VI: Northwest Neighborhood Survey - streets S to W, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      Historic resources inventory sheets Smith St, Starr Ave, Well Ave. Westville Ave. separate photos
    - Phase VI: Northwest Neighborhood Survey - agreements and correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
      Maps, Connecticut Historical Commission grant application correspondence; City of Danbury grant, funding contracts for survey of Northwestern Danbury, 1986
    - Phase VI: Northwest Neighborhood Survey - Long Ridge - Starrs Plain area, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 15-17)
      Long Ridge Rd., passway, Wickes Manor, Dreier house, George Hull Hill Rd, Picketts Ridge, West Redding Rd., East Starrs Plain historical ownership notes, assessor's cards notes
  - Main Street Redevelopment Proposals
    - Errichetti bid materials, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      Invitation to bid, letter to Errichetti 1985, Ramp Consulting parking report, DNT article - picture of Nolans and CC members, prospective bid memorandum, DNT aritcle 1984, DNT aritcle - chooses Sefrius, DNT - Errichettis foes speak at Fitzwilly's breakfast
    - Downtown Danbury Mall photo negatives, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
      picture negatives
    - Errichetti arbitration, 1984-1995 (Box 5, Folder 29-30)
      -American Arbitration Association Brief of respondent, counter claimant City of Danbury; reply brief of City, DPT letter re: Errichetti 1989, 1986. 1984 the Choice editorial, 1985 Nolan letter to Common Council
    - Parcel A development materials, 1973-1983 (Box 5, Folder 32-33)
      The Downtown section 5 of this publication; downtown action plan, DPT position papers, Greater Danbury Chamber of Commerce - Approach to Downtown revitalization, Redvelopment Agency - Memorandum re: parcel A, action plan for downtown organization, State Historic Preservation Officer - information on grants 1980; evaluation of Parcel A development potential, copy of DNTarticle "Danbury an new look coming" 1973, discussion of parking in Errichetti proposal, Redevelopment Agency solicitation, DNT article on Main St. 1980
    - News articles, pamphlets, correspondence re: redevelopment, 1981-1985 (Box 5, Folder 35-37)
      The Choice article from Renews, 1986 letter from DPT, invitation to Scott Zeigler to breakfast, Committee for Proper Development letter, letter to Mayor Dyer about Redevelopment Vacancy, many DNT articles, Nolan News release, 1984, FOI request by Dr. Valluzzo materials, Danbury Redev. Agency winning letter to Errichetti; DNT articles, outline of proposed development, archtecture drawing, DPT letter opposing high rise apt. on Main St, C. G. Engineers - Teaneck NJ materials; DRA correspondence, DNT articles - office space, DNT pamphlets (originals) Annual Reports 1982, 1983.; picture of proposed high rise buildings
    - Errichetti and Nolan Bid Proposals, 1984 (Box OS 1, Folder 16-17)
      2 folders
  - Preservation Initiatives
    - C. D. Parks Property - Tarrywile Park historical survey, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      Conn Historical Commission Connecticut Heritage Landscape Project, Tarrywile Park historic municipal parks survey
    - C. D. Parks Property - Hearthstone, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      Article called "Preliminary considerations on the aesthetic and historical value of the Parks Property Mansions", article "Is it really a castle?"; B&W picture of Hearthstone, negatives strip; correspondence regarding deterioration of Castle, DNT article
    - C. D. Parks Property ownership history, 1895-1987 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      DNT (DEN) articles - copy of Parks obituary -, death of Dr. Wile -, article on completion of Tarrywile; DPT letter to the editor, draft copy of National Register of Historic Places inventory- nomination form
    - The LaRue Building, 240-242 Main St., 1987 (Box 8, Folder 35)
      LaRue building historic preservation application, 30 pictures of interior of building - 240 -242 Miain St. ,pictures of Main St. buildings in 2 envelopes, 2 proof strips, 2 envelopes of negatives
    - St. Mary's Church, Bethel CT, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 47)
      Correspondene regarding old St. Mary's church building, Bethel Ct.
    - Ball and Roller Bearing Co., 1995 (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
      Historic preservation application - inventor Lewis Heim, 20-22 Maple Ave., list of patents, National Register application for Plainville House - Norton, famous machinist, copies of patents, news articles, 7 pictures (8x 10) in 3 envelopes
    - C. D. Parks Property - appraisal report, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 20-21)
      Appraisal report of Parks property by T. A. Wixted, 1983, includes picture, copies of pictures of house, cottage, garage house, Studio, Storage garage, Famhouse on Southern Blvd., house on Brushy Hill, farm buildings, castle, Montessori school
    - C. D. Parks Property: Tarrywile Mansion, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 25-26)
      Historic resources inventory - Norfolk House with picture, National Register form for Tarrywile with copies of pictures; pictures of Tarrywile interior (before renovation) in envelope, negatives of pictures, print (9 x 10) of Tarry wile postcard, correspondence, Designer's show house brochure, letter from State Historical Commission putting property on Register of Historic Places
    - Danbury Union Station, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 28-29)
      Restoration recommendations; National Register of Historic Places inventory - nomination form; historic resources inventory sheets; DNT articles; Historic American Engineering Record (HAER) article; pre-renovation pictures; blueprint of first floor renovation plan
    - Ericson House, 1985-1988 (Box 8, Folder 30-33)
      Saving of Erickson House, Padanarum Rd., move to Maple Ave and Garamella Blvd., pictures and negatives